(MONEY FOR NOTHING BY DIRE STRAITS)
MTV...
RIP: Previously on Yellowstone...
I don't need your permission
to assemble.
This isn't assembling.
This is greeting the President
of the United States.
He's going to endorse Martin.
(MUSIC)
(CATTLE LOWING)
And don't you ever call this work!
Governor of Montana
on the side of a mountain.
sleeping with his boots on.
JOHN: Couldn't have dreamed up
a better death if you paid me.
I can't have Emmett's wife
watch the herd ride in
without him. and no answers.
(CHEERING)
How?
Like a cowboy should.
(SOBBING)
Just trying figure out.
what you're doing here?
Here's my ulterior motive.
Do you wanna hear it?
Get you elected governor
and save this state.
One for the road?
Are you stupid enough to ask me for that
in front of my father?
Be careful.
Careful don't factor too much into this.
See you when you get back.
ROWDY: You know. I've done some
stupid shit in my life.
but this tops it.
I mean. how the hell are we
supposed to keep wolves
from coming after 5.000 calves?
You ain't gonna stop nothing
sitting by that fire.
I'm gonna ride through 'em.
Yeah. great. Go save the day. cowboy.
You know. I could be holding
that girl's ass
in each hand.
but no...
I'm sitting here
in a sage brush with you.
(MUSIC)
What girl?
What do you mean. what girl?
The one you couldn't keep.
(MUSIC)
What are you gonna do. half pint?
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
You never mention her name.
You don't touch her.
You don't fucking talk
to her. you understand?
(MUSIC)
(SHOUTS)
(GRUNTING)
Try to stab me. you fucking coward?
(ROWDY GROANING)
(COUGHING)
Try it again and I will
shoot you where you stand.
(MUSIC)
(LABORED BREATHING)
Here.
You should drink some water.
It hurts... Head's spinning.
Maybe next time you won't
pull a knife in a fist fight.
(RETCHES)
Here. try to drink something.
(GROANS)
I'm hurt bad.
You need to go to the hospital?
I think so.
- Can you ride?
- Yeah.
(GROANS)
(RETCHES)
I'll go get help.
Tell 'em I fell off my horse
and he trampled me.
Or you'll get in a lot of trouble.
(MUSIC)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Rowdy's hurt. Hurt bad.
Where is he?
With the cattle.
Hurt too bad to ride he says.
He get bucked off?
Rip. did he get bucked off?
No sir. he talked about your daughter
in a way he shouldn't
and we fought about it.
He pulled his knife and I hit
him in the head with a rock.
Too hard. I guess...
You wait here.
(CATTLE LOWING)
Here. give it to me.
Here you go.
- He's dead.
- He's dead?
(RIP CRYING)
That ain't gonna help.
Get down off that horse.
Why didn't you just tell me
he fell off his horse?
That's what Rowdy said.
You said never lie to you.
so I didn't.
Well. you're gonna have to lie now.
Or you're going to prison. son.
Rowdy ain't got no family.
He's just a drifter.
We could drop him off
at the train station.
That's putting a lot
of trust in this boy.
Boy's putting a fair amount in us. too.
(CRYING)
Quit fucking crying.
The time to worry about consequences
was before the fight.
There's a thing I could do.
but if I do it. you don't
ever leave this place.
You'll be part of this ranch
until the day you die.
and you will do for
this ranch what I say do.
No matter what that is.
you understand me?
This ranch is the only family I've got.
Ain't ever leaving it
no matter what you do.
All right.
Come help me.
(MUSIC)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
JAMIE: This was not what
I was supposed to be.
I was... I was...
I was raised to be a cowboy.
To... To run a ranch. To...
To know the nuances
of being a cattle producer.
To... You know. from. from...
from understanding the grass cycles.
to... to timing the calving season
to maximize the grass cycles.
Understanding bull genetics
and diseases.
It was...
I never wanted to be a fucking lawyer.
This is what he wanted me to be.
What he thought he needed.
"The future of warfare
is fought with a pen.
"Learn to fight with a pen."
All right. So. I did.
And I did.
And then I get this acceptance
letter from Harvard.
- Hell. I never even applied.
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
He applied for me.
(LAUGHS)
There's no telling who
wrote the fucking essay.
Your sister. I would think.
Never thought of that.
God. why didn't I think of that?
Because you're too close to it.
My father hates me.
Hates me.
He hates me for becoming the very thing
he asked me to become.
No. forced me to be.
Do you care that he hates you?
Is his love something
you feel you really need?
Evidently not. I've lived
without it my whole life.
But I would like his approval.
I want his appreciation
for that fucking sacrifice.
He can't give you that.
He resents the tool
that he relies on the most.
because he can't be that tool.
He's jealous of you. Jamie.
And he's scared of you.
He's scared because
the future of that ranch
depends on its evolution.
If it doesn't evolve with society
it will be devoured by society.
I know. I know.
I've said that for years.
It's been decades.
And he's still running cow-calf pairs
like it's the 1950s.
when cow-calf pairs in the 1950s
didn't even make any money.
Cattle.
Let me tell you the future
of the cattle industry.
Right now. the biggest meat processor
in the United States
is a Brazilian Corporation.
10.000 acres of rainforest
cleared every day.
For what? To raise cattle.
Is that a coincidence?
The future of the beef industry
in the United States
- is no future.
- Mmm-mmm.
In twenty years Brazil
will be to American beef
what China is to American manufacturing.
There will be no more cattle in America.
That's why the airport development
was vital to the ranch's future.
You don't have to tell me that.
- (LAUGHS)
- Mmm-mmm.
But you do have to tell
the rest of Montana.
Tourism is Montana's only resource.
What else do you have. timber?
Cutting down something
it takes 200 years to replace?
That is not a business.
That is self-mutilation.
No. Tourism. That is all you have.
And you can seize it
or you can witness it.
Those are your options.
(MUSIC)
I know.
You love that ranch.
It's the only thing I've ever loved.
Let me help you save it.
I can help you save it
if you want me to.
I do.
Ask me. then.
Ask me to help you save it.
Will you help me?
(WHISPERS) Help me.
Yes.
(WHISPERS) I will help you. baby.
I will help you. baby.
(MUSIC)
Mmm.
(MOUNTAIN SONG BY FLATLAND CAVALRY)
Mountain. mountain
It's good to see your face
Mighty wonder
High above the plains
Mountain. mountain
Could I take your place?
River. river
Take me away
Wash me clean
Keep my sins at bay...
Morning.
We'll be back by noon.
That's usually when I wake up.
And now you're just leavin'.
This job starts early.
I feel so used.
Yeah? That's exactly how I feel.
I'll see you later.
Carrying with me
everything I own and who I am
Pray to God I see your face again...
I'm gonna go back to sleep.
Okay.
You'd better be worth
this walk of shame.
Half my church is camped out here.
Stars are burnin'
Up in the sky
Celestial angels teach me how to fly
Stars are burnin'
Won't you take me on high
Take me on high
Pine tree campfire. end of the night
Embers burnin'. shedding you light
Bottle of Blanton's got me feelin' right
Hey.
I'm not sad. I'm... I'm happy.
(SNIFFS)
You're becoming a man. Tate.
Watching that makes me happy.
You don't have to get up. baby.
Oh. we got a lot of mouths to feed.
Why don't we give your mom
some privacy. okay?
All right.
- Bye. Mom.
- Bye. baby.
(MUSIC)
Thanks. Gator.
Thank you. Gator.
(METAL CLANKING)
(SIGH)
Go. boys.
- RIP: Morning. sir.
- JOHN: Morning.
This is my favorite part.
Of everything we do. this is.
this is my favorite.
Well. I prefer when it's done.
And everything went smooth.
(LAUGHS)
That part just makes me sad it's over.
(MUSIC)
(SNIFFS)
(TENT UNZIPS)
- Morning.
- Hey.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Look at all you sluts.
You're sitting here. too.
I doubt you just wandered down
from the house to take in the view.
Yeah. well. I'm a married woman.
- But you tramps...
- Ah. yes.
That arcane ritual where you stand
before family and friends
and swear before God deity
that you will surrender
your independence
and obey the man you are betrothed to.
(LAUGHS) Betrothed?
See. what Summer's attempting to do here
is make out that marriage
is designed to somehow
oppress and control a woman.
You know. if you married to
a piece of shit. it can be.
but if you married the love
of your life.
the mirror to your soul.
it's pretty fucking great.
I thought we agreed to get along.
We did. I didn't agree to placate
some of your hippie bullshit
where every institution
and every custom is designed to oppress.
They are.
They are what you make 'em. babe.
I'm going to take a shower.
- You could probably use one.
- (LAUGHS)
- Are there showers here?
- Yeah. in the bunkhouse.
I'll show you.
What?
Just waiting for another zinger.
I'm all zinged out for now.
Why are you so mean?
No reason.
Fun.
That's fun for you?
What. to point out the very thing
that everyone's thinking
but they don't have the spine
to own it and say?
"Yeah. damn right I romped
in the tent all night.
You should try it." Which I did.
Most of the night.
Yes. I find that amusing.
Well. I think it's cruel.
Well. that's why I don't do it to you.
Those cowgirls.
they give as good as they get
and that patchouli-scented
know it all. well. she needs it.
You don't need it.
Well. I don't need
to be treated differently
just because I lost a child.
(MUSIC)
Yeah. you do.
I'm gonna tell you something
I haven't told anybody.
so let's keep this between us.
Okay.
I know how you feel
because I've felt it.
And I feel it every day.
So when I say that I am sorry. Monica.
I really mean it.
Thank you.
That's why you're mean.
Because nobody knows.
Because you keep that inside yourself.
I keep it inside because of
all the people knowing it would hurt.
Anyway. that's not why I'm mean.
I was a real fucking bitch
before it happened. so...
Well... You're very good at it.
- I try.
- (CHUCKLES)
(MUSIC)
MAN: Call ya later.
WOMAN: Thanks. yeah. that'd be great.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
It's in here.
Chairman Rainwater.
- Hello.
- Right this way.
- (KNOCKS)
- Chairman Rainwater is here.
Thanks.
- Tom.
- Senator.
Thanks for coming.
Please. sit.
Either of you like coffee?
Well. I'm too curious for coffee.
Well. I'll get right to it. then.
The Department of Interior has approved
two pipelines in central Montana.
One is a natural gas.
and the other is captured carbon
and the proposed pathway
is through the reservation.
(SIGH)
The Secretary of the Interior was here
with the President two days ago.
They mentioned nothing.
As I'm learning.
Federal politics is. well.
they never take the gloves off
because they never put them on.
Is there a map of this pathway?
The pipeline runs beneath our reservoir.
Yes.
Our drinking water.
How is the path chosen?
Well. it's the shortest distance between
two points and the path
of least legal resistance.
To go to the west of you enters
into State land forest service.
east of you is private ranches.
which have the funds to fight.
and likely the support
of our new governor.
They don't think we'll put up a fight?
We can't put up a fight.
Federal Government doesn't
need our permission.
So that my position is clear.
I do not support this.
And I will declare my opposition.
how much weight that holds
in this instance... I...
If there's nothing you can do
and there's nothing I can do.
why are you telling me?
Because I know who's
coming after your office
and they'll use this against you.
At least now. make a statement.
get out in front of it.
Make enough noise that
the Department of Interior
will look somewhere else.
North Dakota. let's say.
That just ruins the land
in North Dakota.
I'm not the Senator of North Dakota.
So that's North Dakota's problem.
I guess you don't put gloves on either.
When will you publicly
declare your opposition?
As soon as the pipeline is made public.
which I assume is when
you'll call a press conference.
You set the press conference.
Stand with the people this affects.
Standing beside you in solidarity
is declaring my support for you
as much as it is opposing a pipeline.
We'll kill two birds with one stone.
Deal.
I'll set it for tomorrow.
Be good to have the governor there.
Well. the governor's playing hooky.
Branding cattle.
That's not what he was elected to do.
Oh. he did what he was elected to do.
That's the way John sees it. anyway.
He's our governor. too.
Perhaps you could remind him of that.
(MUSIC)
LLOYD: Hup. hup.
(WHISTLES)
Sh-sh-sh-sh...
(WHISTLING)
Damn. Lloyd.
What?
That's the third one I've seen.
- One what?
- Stillborn buffalo calf.
- Where?
- He's right back there.
Aw. shit. this ain't gonna be good.
Buffalo from the park
been in this pasture.
Found two dead bison calves
there. stillborn.
Walker said he's seen two more of 'em.
Let me guess.
you found a stillborn bison.
Two.
Why would that happen?
Brucellosis. Clara.
Found something
you're going to want to see.
We found it. too.
Can cattle get it?
Yes. cattle can get it.
Well. how can you tell?
Well. we'll test them for it.
And if one cow has it. the state
destroys the whole herd.
All our cows have calves.
We're not going to solve
this on the side of the hill.
Let's get em to headquarters.
We'll figure it out there.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
(LET IT OUT BY L.A. EDWARDS)
Gonna cast a long black shadow
Over you and all white chapel...
Open her up.
Nobody gonna hear you shatter
(CATTLE LOWING)
Bad moon rising overhead
Bad blood running through my head
Little mama. you sure look fine
But you're sleeping on your own tonight
Yeah. you're sleeping
on your own tonight...
Good cut. Jake. Good job. buddy.
All saints. all sinners...
Just push it in. Simple job.
- That'll do.
- All right. boys. good job.
Let's go ahead
and push them up the chute.
Hep. hep. hep.
Yeah. that's all the cows.
Good to let it out...
(CATTLE LOWING)
Little mama's baby boy
Little mama. you're my pride and joy
Wanna put you out on display
Little mama. I'm on my way...
Whatever's left. we're going
to brand and castrate.
Little mama. I'm on my way
All saints. all sinners...
There you go.
All the same...
TEETER: Woo! You jumping in on this?
- You doing it?
- CLARA: Yep.
- Hell yeah.
- All right. come on.
- TEETER: Ready?
- CLARA: Right.
Right side on one. two. three.
Get him over good.
- Got him?
- Yep.
Great. man. look at
the fuckin' girl power.
Gun powder? For what?
Girl power. Fucking girl power. man!
You speak fucking English?
What the fuck are you saying?
- Fuck it.
- Just do it!
Come on. little miss sunshine.
I'm so fucking sorry. little calf.
It's for your own good
so you don't get sick.
I'm sorry. I'm so fucking sorry.
Sorry. sorry.
I feel like I shouldn't be
watching. but I can't stop.
It's riveting.
(GROANING)
- This is so fucking traumatizing.
- (COW YELPS)
We're up.
All saints. all sinners...
(COW LOWING)
You tell me when you're ready for me.
- Oh. my God!
- We're ready.
Yeah. okay. (GAGS)
Oh. this is fucking traumatizing.
Ooh hoo hoo!
You ever seen one with blackleg?
- No.
- That's traumatizing.
You are doing the calf a big favor.
And if you could do
that favor a little faster.
- Okay.
- Come on!
I'm sorry. little calf.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
- Okay. set?
- Yep.
(LAUGHING)
If the state kills the herd.
do they pay you back?
Not what it's worth.
The herd's insured but... I don't know.
I don't know how we rebuild
a hundred years of genetics.
Look. if one of them tests positive.
there's nothing we can do.
Start over. I guess.
But if they don't.
we got a bigger problem.
We can't use that south pasture.
There's fifty miles of fence to check.
that lower valley's too dry.
they got nothing to eat.
We wean early. send the calves
to a back grounding yard
in Nebraska. or...
The trucking will kill us. Kayce.
and we're already paying
a gain on top of it.
What about hayin' 'em?
Yeah. and feed 'em
with what in the winter?
Son of a bitch.
Look. I'll. um...
I'll start making some calls.
Find us some lease ground.
You know. to make this pencil out
half the herd needs to go.
needs to stay a year or more.
Lease ground where?
Somewhere with a mild winter.
I'll start making some calls.
If half the herd goes. who watches 'em?
(CHUCKLES) Who do you think. Kayce?
RIP: Lloyd.
Well. what's the plan?
Mister Dutton
wants to lease land down south
and get the herd out.
I'll go with the herd.
Who else you gonna take?
I don't know. Who you want to stay here?
Hell. you're the one living
out of a teepee in new country.
you take who you want.
All right.
I'll go with Jake.
Teeter. Ryan.
and hell. I'll take Walker.
You ain't gonna kill him
out there on the plains
somewhere. are you?
We're probably going
to his old stomping ground.
I might need someone that
knows some folks down there.
By the way. I'm more fucking worried
about you killing his ass.
My memory's not as mean as yours.
(CHUCKLES)
You're gonna be a long way from home.
Long way from your wife.
I ain't got nobody. you oughta send me.
I'm ranch manager. Lloyd.
It's my responsibility.
I appreciate it. though.
Well. when you are you leaving?
Soon as Mr. Dutton signs the lease
and I get the trucks lined up.
- You're gonna need Gator.
- Go tell him. will ya?
Jake. Walker.
Ryan. Teeter.
Get over here.
All right. listen up.
After we brand these cattle.
we're going to hold them here.
then we're gonna put them on trucks.
we're going to take them
to lease ground.
You four are coming with me.
We're gonna get some day workers
when we get down there.
- Where?
- I don't know.
Somewhere where it doesn't
snow in the winter.
Go and pack up everything you got.
Your teepees. all of it.
We'll be gone for a while.
What are you smiling about?
Gonna go do some cowboy shit now.
You keep that bunkhouse and cable TV.
Thanks for picking us. boss.
- Yes. sir.
- Thank you. sir.
You got it.
(MUSIC)
Ryan.
I want you to tell me right now
if this is going to be a problem.
I don't want to hear about it
in some canyon in New Mexico.
There's nothin' I'd rather do.
Sir. thank you for the chance.
You got it.
Ryan. Ryan. hold on a second.
Why don't you take
the bunkhouse to the fair.
You go have some fun.
You ain't gonna see
a town in a long while.
Thank you.
(GROANS)
That's Swarovski crystal. Dad.
Swarovski makes optics. honey.
With the glass
from their crystal factory.
Yeah. well. I need to break something.
That is a hundred years old
and belonged to your grandfather.
Break something else.
(DRINK POURING)
Need to move our herd down south.
Buffalo herd left the park.
Spent spring on our ranch.
Herd has brucellosis now.
That sounds ominous.
It is.
How far south?
Far enough that it doesn't snow.
so we don't have
to feed them all winter.
Okay. so do you have to lease the land?
- Yeah.
- And how much will that cost?
Dry as it is? I don't know.
12. 14 dollars an acre.
Okay. how many acres?
Depends on the land.
Hundred thousand at least.
So that's 1.4 million dollars a year.
No. Beth.
1.4 a month.
Dad. we don't...
We don't have that.
I know. I'll take a loan.
Why don't you just sell them all now?
If we sell 'em all now.
we have no income next year.
We don't have any income this year.
We have no profit this year.
We have no profit any year.
(MUSIC)
Now I want to break shit.
(GLASS CLINKS)
If we sell the heifers and
the steers. what is that worth?
If I can get them to weigh
750. worth about 1100 dollars.
Okay. so that's a $1.50 a pound. Dad.
Yep.
A good steak is worth
thirty bucks a pound.
shitty ground beef is worth five.
We don't sell beef. we sell cattle.
Exactly. We're in the wrong
fucking business.
You know. I really. uh...
I really thought the airport would be
the end of us. Dad. but
your business model.
is gonna be the end of us.
Business model's
worked for a hundred years...
No. Dad. it hasn't worked.
If it worked. this fucking
valley wouldn't be filled
with hobby farms and vacation houses.
It would be filled with ranches.
People don't sell businesses
that make money. right?
They sell the losers.
(SNIFFS)
(MUSIC)
(EXHALES)
Randy. John Dutton. How are ya?
You all stocked up?
Yeah. I need some ground.
Five thousand if I can find the grass.
Yeah. I know him.
Who else if that doesn't work?
Oh. um. Ellis Steele is in
your office with Miss Atwood.
Sarah?
That's weird.
Can I say something. that's...
That I don't have a right to say?
Sure?
Women know women.
Men know what a woman
wants them to know.
I worry about you being with her.
Oh. I'm not...
Who told you I was with her?
You're with her.
Thank you for saying something.
I'll keep it in mind.
This is
unexpected.
Um...
What's on your mind. Mr. Steele?
This.
Your father put his ranch
in the Land Trust.
He put the land in a
conservation easement. Jamie.
How could you let him do that?
Well. I...
I...
I didn't know.
Do you have the authority
to override that?
Theoretically. yes.
But...
You're not battling a man. anymore.
you're battling the legal defense funds
of environmental groups.
which had no basis to sue you.
but now they are the stewards of the...
Fuck!
God damn it!
Thank you for coming.
I'm going to need some time
to process this information.
(MUSIC)
Market Equities will sue the state
for a bad faith negotiation.
They will file it in
federal court in New York.
where they incurred the damages.
and those attorneys will
wipe the floor with you.
Your state will be on the hook
for around 4 billion dollars
in compensatory damages.
That's ten percent of Montana's GDP.
The state's gonna go bankrupt.
(MUSIC)
Sounds like an
impeachable offense to me.
Yes. it does.
What's the procedure in Montana
when a Governor resigns or steps down?
You have a special election.
We're fully committed to your election.
Our PAC will fund it.
Go before the Assembly.
This is your chance to become governor.
and get our fucking land back.
(MUSIC)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(RINGING)
MAN: Supply House.
Is this the number to order beef?
Yes. ma'am. but you can do it online.
Can I be nosey?
Umm. sure.
Is this your beef.
that you raise and sell online?
Yes. ma'am. Some comes
from neighboring ranchers
'cause we sell out of all ours.
but they follow the same program.
You sell out?
Yes. ma'am.
How many pounds of beef do you raise?
This year. a little over 8 million.
What's the catch?
Ma'am?
There's always a catch.
No catch.
You just gotta have enough
money to feed your herd
for two years before you make any money.
Or get a big loan.
And have a lot of backbone. ma'am.
Backbone we got. Thank you.
JOHN: Joe. I can't thank you enough.
Once I get the trucks lined up
I'll start sending 'em your way.
This is what you get your loan for.
The cash flow is impossible. honey.
and nobody can figure out the packer.
They figured out the packer.
Do you know this ranch?
Yeah. I was just on
the phone with this ranch.
So was I.
They sold 8 million pounds of beef.
On a website.
I don't know what their
arrangement is honey.
but one thing I do know is
nobody has ever been able
to figure out the re-packer.
That is because you are not
a businessman. Daddy.
You are a rancher.
I am a businessman.
And I have spent my career making
fifty. hundred million
dollar deals for others.
Now I'm gonna make one for you.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Sir?
Line up the trucks.
They're lined up.
We just need to know
where they're headed.
Ground in Eastern Colorado
and north of Panhandle in Texas.
Okay. Sweetheart...
Don't bite my head off
for asking this question.
I don't like the way this is starting.
Me either...
Um... Would you like to come
to the fair with me?
Sure. when?
Yes? Really?
Yeah. why wouldn't I want
to go to the fair?
Is fair some sort of metaphor
for something a father
shouldn't be hearing?
No. no. It's the fair.
It's the county fair.
It's been happening
for the last 92 years. sir.
- I'll get my sweater.
- Okay. sweetie.
So. you're talking
about going to the fair.
Yes. sir. Yeah.
Yeah. that's a great idea.
(DEEP BREATH)
Carter. go on and get washed up.
We're going to go to the fair.
Come on.
How long you gonna be gone?
Well. until we don't want to
be there. What do you mean?
I mean down south.
A while.
How long's a while?
I don't know. son.
Now go on. Get washed up.
(MUSIC)
(MOTORCYCLE DRIVE-BY
BY ZACH BRYAN PLAYS)
(SHOUTING)
It's the motorcycle drive-by
Baby. dry your kind eyes
I think it's about time we headed home
Walking on such tight rope
With my damn high hopes
Country boys don't die alone
Every day's so fleeting
And I have been trying
To save it while I can
Look on her face
all these hot humid days
And the boys in my damn band
It's the motorcycle drive-by
Baby. dry your kind eyes
I think it's about time we headed home
Walking such a tight rope
With my damn high hopes
Country boys don't die alone
Hey. Are you all right with
people taking our picture?
You're my environmental
advisor. all right?
Try to resist the temptation
to jump my bones
and we'll be all right.
I'll see if I can control myself.
- You do that.
- (LAUGHS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
There he is.
You're good.
Thanks.
What?
Nuthin'.
Wanna go see the band?
You bet.
(INDISTINCT CARNIVAL BARKING)
Tate. honey. why don't
you stay with Carter. okay?
All right. Can we have more money?
All right.
Make it last.
Make it last?
A hot dog here is nine dollars.
Thanks.
Think we reached the point
where we're just
a bank and a taxi.
Before you know it. he'll be the taxi.
Hey. He's about to win me a fuckin' bar.
Let's go. right here.
Right here. I want that fuckin' bar.
That fuckin' bar right there.
All these games are rigged.
Who gives a shit? I want it!
Why don't I just give you
the thirty dollars
it's gonna cost me to win the bear?
Give me the bar. Come on.
Hi. what's up?
Can you explain this game to me?
All you gotta do is toss three balls
in the center hole.
you can take your prize.
- All right.
- Sounds delightful.
You get it in
the hole all the time at home.
- Let's do it just like home.
- There's kids around. relax.
You got this. baby. Come on.
Just throw it.
Fuck. that just went in.
That went in?
Yes. sir. Right in.
Okay. but. nobody gets two in a row.
so it doesn't really matter...
Whatever. you want to step
closer and get me my bar. let's go.
Give me two more of those.
- (LAUGHING)
- Right in!
Fuck yeah! One more!
- That went in?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay wait. so. if I get this.
then I win?
Yes. sir.
Whoa. whoa. whoa.
Don't start trying now.
Just throw it like you been throwing it.
Yeah. but I haven't even been looking.
Then don't look.
Right here. you just do
that same thing again.
- Fuck it.
- Right here.
Whoo! Fuck yeah. baby!
Mama gonna be so good tonight.
What's wrong with you?
There's kids around!
Give me my bar.
Come on. man. you give me
my fuckin' bar.
- She wants the bear.
- MAN: Got it.
- That's what I said.
- TEETER: Give me that thing.
- All right.
I love my bar!
(SUMMERTIME BLUES BY ZACH BRYAN)
The sun set so late tonight
I wonder if you saw it. too
Wish I still had someone to lose
All I got are these summertime blues
Bet there's a green-eyed
dark-haired beauty
On some beach by Monterey
Lettin' waves wash her pain away
But I'll never know
Bet there's some boys out in Okie...
How long will you be gone?
I don't know.
Well. ball-park it.
- Maybe a year.
- A year?
Honey. I can't live
without you for a year.
Beth. I know it's gonna be tough.
No. I mean it.
I won't survive that.
You wanna live in a canvas tent?
For a year?
Take a fuckin' shower once
a week in a Motel 6?
Come on now.
Well. we swore to spend
our lives together.
Where you go. I go.
I'm gonna do what the fuck
I wanna do anyway. so...
I'm well aware of that. sweetheart.
All right. so it's settled.
How long is the drive?
I mean. hauling horses.
I'd say probably 20 hours.
- 20?
- Mmm-hmm.
How far away is the nearest city?
Maybe an hour.
All right. well. I'll fly
and meet your ass there.
(CHUCKLES) Listen. the easiest thing
about cowboying is hauling
horses. sweetie.
Well. I'm not doing
any cowboying. You are.
I'm gonna rent a suite
at the nearest Hyatt
and I'll drive to you for Happy Hour.
Oh. really?
Hauling hay. fightin' off the sun
Ladies waitin' in town
My summertime blues
Summertime blues
I've got nothing left to prove
Out of touch and out of tune
Singin' alone...
So how long do you think
y'all gonna be gone for?
Hell. it'll take at least
a year for it to pencil out.
You're going to Texas for a year?
You didn't care to mention that?
We just found out today.
Abby.
(SIGHS)
I've got nothing left to prove...
Abby?
Abby!
To the birds up high
and the souls below...
Abby.
- Abigail.
- Did you quit your job?
Why would I do that?
Did you demand to stay
on the ranch here?
I'm sure someone is...
Look. I don't see the point
in you running after me
if you don't have something
different to tell me.
- Abby. you don't understand...
- Then explain it to me.
- You sing in the shower?
- I sing everywhere.
Mmm-hmm.
Cowboying. That's how I sing.
If the Grand Ol' Oprey
is your Super Bowl.
then moving five thousand head
to land we don't know
and keeping that herd together.
and protectin' them through winter.
and new predators
and new diseases. that's mine.
To the birds up high and the souls below
All those boys who ain't got no home
The beautiful girls I'll never hold
This one's for you...
Chasing a dream. I understand.
And I hope you catch it.
I just wish that dream was me.
Bought a bottle of the best bourbon
A beat down boy could buy
Gonna bury all my sorrow
As the summertime passes
My summertime blues
Summertime blues
I've got nothing left to prove
Out of touch and out of tune
Singing alone...
You don't like the band?
Hmm?
The band?
Oh. he's... He's good.
- Just...
- You look sad.
You know I look at.
look at all these people...
This is dying.
It's already dead where you're from.
But now all the people where
you're from are
coming out here and I can't...
(LAUGHS) I can't stop it.
Okay.
Have you tried?
Well. that's. um.
why I became governor.
You ran for governor to stop
an airport in a subdivision
and you did that in one day.
What I never understood about you guys
is all you do is bitch
about how much people
move into rural America. ruin it.
change the culture.
but I've lived all over
the mountain west.
Gunnison. Santa Fe.
Jackson Hole. Telluride.
and not once.
never once
did my neighbor bring me to a branding
or the fair.
(LAUGHS)
Or the harvest or whatever
community ritual is happening.
they just glared at my hiking
shorts and my license plate
and judged me.
Same way I judged you.
I've got nothing left to prove
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not ordering a steak
for dinner any time soon.
But I understand now.
I understand why you brand
and why you vaccinate
and why you move them
from one pasture to another.
Twelve million tourists a year
come to Montana from cities.
You might wanna think about
inviting a few of them over
so they understand who you really are
and what you really do
because they have you pegged
as a bunch of misogynist bigots
who are ruining the environment
and that is not who you are.
You're a smart woman. Summer.
Very. very smart woman.
I'm a smart person.
(SIGH)
Well. women are smarter than men
to begin with so I'm just
judging you against your peers.
Thanks for kidnapping me.
I'm really enjoying it.
(LAUGHS) I didn't...
I did not kidnap you... I commuted
your sentence to house arrest.
At your house.
(EXHALES)
I guess in the narrowest
of legal interpretations
maybe
you're right.
Thanks for doing it.
My summertime blues...
As your press advisor
I suggest you postpone that look.
You're my environmental advisor.
My press advisor's
behind me. making out.
Bought a bottle of the best bourbon
a beat down...
You have no intention
of running for a second term do you?
Absolutely zero.
What is it about sad songs and cowboys?
All those boys who ain't got no home...
I don't care what they think.
You made that abundantly clear.
Well. there's no one in front of us.
Very few to my right
and everyone to my left is with me.
That just leaves the 1.500 behind us.
(GRUNTS) Oh yeah.
Yeah. Well...
I think you're gonna like this trick.
All I got are these summertime blues
(APPLAUSE)
"The actions of Governor Dutton
have not only robbed Montanans
"of six thousand jobs and
annual revenue in the billions.
"his actions have exposed
Montana to litigation
"that will cost the state billions more.
"likely bankrupting the state.
"Which robs your children
of school funding.
"robs our towns of emergency services.
"places our roads and
infrastructure in disrepair.
"It threatens the quality
of life for all Montanans.
"After weighing his actions
and the cost of those actions
"for every Montanan.
"I call on this assembly
for a vote to impeach.
"Mister Speaker. what say ye?"
(EXHALES) What do you think?
I think it's perfect.
(MUSIC)
NARRATOR: Next time on the mid-season
finale of Yellowstone...
JAMIE: The greatest threat
to that ranch is our father.
So I will remove the threat.
I got something to ask Kayce.
I need his help.
I need it from all of ya.
Governor Dutton has violated state law.
The Attorney General's office
is seeking impeachment.
BETH: He has declared war upon us.
- I'm aware. Beth.
- (CLOCK TICKING)
(MUSIC)